So the first step is to figure out a way for
لذلك فالخطوة الأولى لإيجاد طريقة
the Word Adapter to tell if the word object has an image or not.
لمعرفة موائم النص إذا ما كان يوجد بكائن النص صورة أم لا.
So let's take a look at the Word Adapter file and Android studio.
لذلك لنلق نظرة على ملف موائم النص وآندرويد ستوديو.
Now here the Word Adapter class, remember that we only want to
وإليك الآن فئة موائم النص، تذكر أننا فقط نريد
execute these lines of code that set up the ImageView, if there is an image for
تنفيذ خطوط الكود هذه التي تعد واجهة الصورة، إذا كان هناك صورة
the word.
للورد.
In order to do this, we should create and expose another method in the Word
من أجل القيام بذلك، علينا إنشاء وظيفة أخرى والتعرض لها في فئة
class, which should tell us if the word at the current position has an image.
النص، التي يجب أن نعرف من خلالها إذا ما كان النص يحتوي على صورة في الوضع الحالي.
So I want to hop over to work class and define that method.
لذلك أرغب في التنقل داخل فئة العمل وتعريف هذه الوظيفة.
So at the bottom of the word class, I'm going to create a public method called
لذلك سأقوم في أسفل فئة النص بإنشاء وظيفة عام تُسمى
hasImage and have it return a boolean value.
"داخلها صورة" وإرجاعها كقيمة منطقية.
So I want this method to turn true, if the word has an image and
أرغب في استخدام هذه الوظيفة لتكون حقيقية، إذا ما كان بالنص صورة، وخاطئة
false, if there is no image, and remember it's important to always add
إذا لما يكن به صورة، وتذكر أنه من المهم دائمًا إضافة
some comments to help readers understand your code I'm going to add that here.
بعض التعليقات لمساعدة القراء في فهم كودك والذي سأضيفها هنا.
Now how should we determine if a word has an image?
والآن كيف يجب أن نحدد إذا ما كان بالنص صورة؟
Well let's scroll up to the top of the word class.
فلنمرر لأعلى فئة النص.
And remember that we had this variable here,
وتذكر أن لدينا هذا المتغير هنا،
mImageResourceId and we can check that.
معرف مورد صورتي ويمكننا فحص ذلك.
We'll note that it doesn't actually help us predict what image is referenced.
سنلاحظ أنه لن يساعدنا بالفعل في التنبؤ بأي صورة تمت الإشارة إليها.
However in our case, we only need to use it to check whether or
وبالرغم من ذلك في حالتنا، يجب علينا فقط استخدامه للتحق من إذا كان يوجد
not there is a valid image.
صورة صالحة أو لا يوجد.
All right so this is actually a really good use case for constant values.
حسنًا هذه حالة استخدام صالحة بالفعل للقيم الثابتة.
We can create a constant that represents the no image state, and
يمكننا إنشاء قيمة ثابتة تمثل حالة عدم وجود صورة، وسوف
I'm going to do that here.
أقوم بذلك.
So I created a variable called NO_IMAGE_PROVIDED, it's in all caps
لذلك يمكنني إنشاء متغير يُسمى "لا توجد صورة"،
because it's a constant, and each word is separated by an underscore.
لأنه ثابت ويتم الفصل بين الكلمات بعلامة "_".
Now I'm going to set this to a constant value of negative one, and
الآن سأقوم بوضع ذلك للقيمة الثابتة للحالة السلبية،
I use negative one,
وساستخدم حالة سلبية واحدة،
because it's out of the range of all the possible valid resource ID.
لأنه خارج نطاق جميع معرفات الموارد الصالحة الممكنة.
Also notice that this constant is a private variable,
لاحظ أيضًا أن هذا الثابت متغير خاص،
because we only need to use it within the word class.
لأننا نحتاج لاستخدامه فقط داخل فئة النص.
So with this constant created,
لذلك عند إنشاء هذا الثابت،
I'm going to set the image variable to start at the no image state by default.
سأقوم بوضع متغير الصورة للبدء بحالة "لا توجد صورة" افتراضيًا.
So I'm going to set that equal to our no image constant here.
سأقوم بوضع هذا الثابت المساوي لثابت حالة "لا توجد صورة" هنا.
Now as soon as this variable's updated to something else,
والآن بمجرد تحديث هذا المتغير لشيء آخر،
we know that the Word has an image.
نعلم أن النص به صورة.
So this means that if there is an image in this contractor,
حيث يعني ذلك وجود صورة في هذا المنظم،
this variable will be updated to something else, and
سيتم تحديث هذا المتغير لشيء آخر
you would know that the word has an image and otherwise if no image is from
وستعرف أن النص به صورة، وخلاف ذلك في حالة عدم وجود صورة
right in, then the image resource ID will say the same.
وسيظهر ذلك في معرف مورد الصورة.
So, remain with the constant value negative one.
لذا ابق مع الحالة السلبية لقيمة الثابت.
So, let's go back down to the has image method, which we still need to complete.
لذا فلنمرر للأسفل إلى وظيفة الصورة التي يجب علينا إكمالها.
So, in this method we just need to check whether the image variable is equal or
لذا نحتاج في هذه الوظيفة فحص متغير الصورة إذا كان مساويًا أو
not equal to the no image provided constant, and that will like this and
غير مساوٍ لثابت حالة "عدم وجود صورة"،
by the way the exclamation mark followed by the equal sign means not equal to.
ولذلك تظهر علامة التعجب بعد علامة التساوي تعني عدم التساوي.
So the result of this expression will be either true or false, and
لذلك نتيجة هذا التعبير تكون أما صحيح أو خاطئ،
that value gets returned as the return value of this method.
ويتم إرجاع القيمة كقيمة إرجاع لهذا الوظيفة.
So no logic can be a little bit confusing, but I like you to try and
لذلك عدم وجود منطق يعد محيرًا بعض الشيء، لكن أود أن تحاول
follow along.
وتتابع الخطوات.
So if the image resource variable is not equal to negative one,
لذلك إذا لم يكن متغير مورد الصورة مساويًا للحالة السلبية،
then there is a valid image, and the method should return true, however if
فإن هناك صورة صالحة ويجب إرجاع الوظيفة إلى الحالة الحقيقة،
the image variable Is equal to negative one then there is no image for
وإذا كان متغير الصورة مساويًا للحالة السلبية، فإنه لا توجد صورة لهذا النص
this word and the method to return false.
ويتم إرجاع الوظيفة إلى الحالة الخاطئة.
Now we don't want to force the word adopter class to do the quality check,
الآن لا نرغب في عمل فئة موائم النص للقيام بالتحقق من الجودة،
because all it cares about is whether or not there is an image.
حيث إن كل الاهتمام ينصب حول وجود صورة من عدمه.
So the word adapter doesn't need to know all the nitty gritty details of how we
لا يحتاج موائم النص لمعرفة أدق التفاصيل حول كيفية
used to cost in our world class decide this.
إعدادنا للتكلفة في فئتنا العالمية.
And hence this is why all the logic is within the work class.
ومن ثم فإن المنطق يظهر داخل فئة العمل.
All right. So good job so far.
حسنًا. عمل رائع على كل حال.
Now in the word class we have exposed a public method called hasImage.
الآن سنتعرض في فئة النص لوظيفة عامة تُسمى بـ "توجد صورة".
So let's switch back over to the word adapter class and
لذلك سنعود إلى فئة موائم النص
see how we can use this hasImage method on the word object.
ونرى كيفية استخدام وظيفة "توجد صورة" هذه في كائن النص.
So now this line of code they were concerned with.
والآن يساورهم القلق حيال سطر الكود هذا.
Remember that we can use conditional logic, such as an if else statement.
تذكر أننا نستخدم المنطق الشرطي، مثل جملة لو.
So that our code behaves differently depending on whether or
لذلك يظهر الكود بشكل مختلف طبقًا لحالة وجود صورة
not the word has an image.
في النص أو عدم وجود صورة فيه.
So this if statement checks that if the current word has an image,
وذلك إذا تم التحقق من الجملة في حالة وجود صورة بالنص الحالي،
then we can proceed as we did before and set the correct image
يمكننا الشروع كما فعلنا سابقًا وضع الصورة الصحيحة
from the word object on to the image view, and otherwise if that's not true,
من كائن النص على واجهة الصورة، وغير ذلك إذا لم يكن صحيحًا،
we should hide the image view and that will go in our else statement.
ويجب إخفاء واجهة الصورة والتي ستبدأ في جملتنا أيضًا.
So earlier, I showed you some code on how to change the visibility of a view
قمت بعرض بعض الأكواد قبل ذلك حيال تغيير رؤية الواجهة
when the app is running.
عند تشغيل التطبيق.
So remember using the set visibility method,
لذلك تذكر استخدام وظيفة رؤية الضبط،
we can completely hide the image, so to do so I'm going to set it to gone.
يمكننا إخفاء الصورة بالكامل، وللقيام بذلك سأقوم بضبط ذلك على "تم".
So either through experimentation or reading the documentation on your own.
وذلك عبر التجربة أو قراء التوثيق بنفسك.
I hope you found out that gone means that the view is hidden and
آمل أن تكتشف أن "تم" تعني إنه تم إخفاء الرؤية
doesn't take up any space in the layout.
وإنها لا تشغل أي مساحة في المخطط.
Now compare this with the invisible state which means that the view is
والآن قارن ذلك بالحالة غير المرئية التي تعني إنه تم
hidden but still takes up space in the layout.
إخفاء الرؤية ولكنه ستشغل مساحة في المخطط.
In our up if we set the image view to be invisible there would be a blank space
قمنا بضبط واجهة الصورة في تطبيقنا حتى تكون غير مرئية وستظهر مساحة فارغة
left on the left hand side of the list item and we don't want that.
متبقية على الجانب الأيسر من عناصر القائمة.
So instead we've set the image view to gone, so that hides it completely.
لذلك سنقوم بضبط واجهة الصورة على "تم"، حتى يتم إخفاؤها بالكامل.
Here I'm want to add some comments describing what this line of code does.
أرغب في إضافة بعض التعليقات التي تصف ما يعني سطر الكود هذا.
[BLANK_AUDIO]
[BLANK_AUDIO]
Now back in the if statement.
والآن نعود إلى جملة لو.
We need to be extra explicit code and set the visibility to be visible.
نحتاج إلى كود واضح إضافي وضبط الرؤية على وضع مرئي.
If we do have an image before we do this because views get reused.
إذا كان لدينا صورة قبل القيام بذلك، فإن ذلك يرجع إلى إعادة استخدام الواجهات.
So if the view was previously hidden, we want to make sure that it's made visible
لذلك إذا تم إخفاء الواجهة مسبقًا، فإننا نرغب في التأكد من إنه مرئي
again when we set a new image on the image view.
مرة أخرى عند ضبط صورة جديدة على واجهة الصورة.
All right there were a lot of changes but
توجد الكثير من التغييرات لكن
let's test our device down see what happen.
لنختبر جهازنا ونرى ماذا سيحدث.
All right so first testing and phrases.
حسنًا لنبدأ بالاختبار أولاً.
All right that looks good, no images.
حسنًا يبدو ذلك جيدًا، لا توجد صور.
Now let's try numbers.
الآن لنحاول تجربة الأرقام.
Nice.
حسنًا.
Images.
الصور.
Family members.
أفراد العائلة.
Cool, got those cute faces there.
رائع، ضع هذه الوجوه الجميلة هناك.
And then colors.
ثم الألوان.
That's got the nice spectrum.
لقد حصل ذلك على الزخم الكبير.
So, perfect, so all our categories are functioning as we hoped.
رائع، إن جميع الفئات تعمل كما ينبغي.
So going back to the quiz.
لذا فلنرجع إلى الاختبار.
Let's answer these two questions.
لنجيب عن هذين السؤالين.
So for the phrase list item,
بالنسبة لعنصر قائمة العبارة،
the image view needs to be gone, because we want to hide it.
يجب أن تكون حالة واجهة الصورة "تم"، لأننا نرغب في إخفائها.
And we don't want to take up any space in the layout.
ونرغب في ألا تشغل أي مساحة في المخطط.
That way the two text views can shift all the way to the left.
بهذه الطريقة يمكن تحويل واجهتي النص إلى الجانب الأيسر.
Now for all the other list items.
والآن بالنسبة لعناصر القائمة الأخرى.
The image view needs to be set to visible.
يجب ضبط واجهة الصورة على الوضع المرئي.
So that the user can see it.
حتى يتسن للمستخدم رؤيتها.
So this reflects what we did in our code.
ويوضح ذلك ما قمنا به في كودنا.
And our app looks the way we want it to.
ويظهر تطبيقنا بالطريقة التي نرغب بها.
So really great job on this very challenging quiz.
لقد كان عملاً رائعًا لإنجاز هذا الاختبار الصعب.